# SILVINA VARELA

## **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

P Buenos Aires, Argentina

#### LINKS

silvina-varela.github.io/portfolio github.com/silvina-varela gitlab.com/silvina-varela linkedin.com/in/silvinavarela

#### ABOUT ME

I am a founder at Anka Coop, a software development cooperative based in Argentina. With over 1 year of experience as a Full Stack Developer, I specialize in creating web applications using React and Node.js. Additionally, I bring over 10 years of expertise in team collaboration and project management, contributing to the success of diverse projects.

### **EDUCATION**

Full Stack Web Developing Certificate | Henry Bootcamp (2022)

**Degree in Editing and Book Publishing |**University of Buenos Aires (2012-2016)

Web Design Workshop | Da Vinci (2016)

Adobe Illustrator Workshop | Da Vinci (2015)

#### SKILLS

JavaScript. PHP. HTML. CSS. UI libraries

React, Redux

Node. Express. Laravel

PostgreSQL. MongoDB. Firebase

Agile Methodologies. Scrum. Git

Figma. Adobe InDesign, Photoshop & Illustrator

### LANGUAGES

Spanish (Native)

English (C2 Proficient)

Italian (B1 Intermediate)

#### WORK HISTORY

#### Frontend React Developer and Project Manager | Freelance

Oct. 2023 - Present

- Spearheading the development of a Tango class scheduling app, leveraging React.js and Firebase.
- Successfully designed the prototype and user stories for the Minimum Viable Product (MVP).
- · Managing project timelines, milestones, and client interactions

## FullStack Developer and Team Leader | Open Lab Automata

Feb. 2023 - Present

- Leading an agile development team in the creation of an open-source web app for controlling a pipetting robot.
- Utilizing technologies such as React, Redux, Node, MongoDB, d3, and socket.io.

GitLab Repository

### **Laravel Developer** | Cefeperes

April 2023-Present

- Integrated the WhatsApp API to develop a bot for sending surveys to clients.
- Collected and analyzed client responses.
- Designed a new page flow to enhance user experience.

GitHub Repository

#### Frontend Developer | Plan21 Foundation

Dec. 2022-Feb.2023 (Voluteer position)

• Created a prototype in Figma and developed new features for a web application using React.

#### Frontend Developer | E-commerce project

Sept.-Oct. 2022

- Worked with an agile team, managing the GitHub repository and JIRA.
- Developed features using React.js, MUI, and Tailwind.

#### OTHER WORK EXPERIENCE

## Copyeditor, Proofreader & Typesetter | Eterna Cadencia, 2016-2023

- Managed various stages of the editorial process for both fiction and nonfiction books, averaging at least one project per month.
- Revised translations to guarantee linguistic precision.

#### Senior Book Editor | Biblos Publishing House, Jan. 2016- June 2022

- Led a team of copyeditors and designers, overseeing the entire production process.
- Managed the schedule and served as the main liaison between authors and the publishing house.
- Responsible for timely delivery of approximately 5 books per month in the fields of Social Sciences and Philosophy.

Freelance Translator (English <> Spanish) | 2016-2022

**Teaching Assistant** | University of Buenos Aires, 2017-2019

**Assistant Book Editor** | Eterna Cadencia Publishing House, 2013-2016